<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<introContent>
  	<extensionContent id="net.bioclipse.intro.workbench" style="css/intro.css" name="Bioclipse Workbench" path="overview/@">
		<group style-id="content-group" id="workbench-group">
       		<link label="What is Bioclipse?" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showPage?id=whatisBioclipse" id="mainitem" style-id="content-link">
          		<text>Bioclipse is a complete workbench and platform for life science. Learn here what this means.</text>
       		</link>
       		<link label="Bioclipse concepts" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showPage?id=bioclipseConcepts" id="mainitem" style-id="content-link">
          		<text>Learn the basic Bioclipse concepts, such as View, Editor, Perspective etc.</text>
       		</link>
       		<link label="Licensing" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showPage?id=licenses" id="mainitem" style-id="content-link">
          		<text>A description and statements of copyright and licenses in Bioclipse.</text>
       		</link>
       		<link label="Download additional features" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/runAction?pluginId=net.bioclipse.ui&amp;class=net.bioclipse.ui.actions.LaunchUpdateIntroAction" id="updateitem" style-id="content-link">
          		<text>Search, download, and install additional features from one or more Bioclipse update sites.</text>
       		</link>
       		<link label="Go to workbench but keep introduction open" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/setStandbyMode?standby=true" id="mainitem">
   		         <text>Go to workbench but keep introduction window open on side for assistance</text>
            </link>
       		<link label="Documentation" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showPage?id=documentation" id="mainitem" style-id="content-link">
            	<text>The various ways for finding out about the different sources of documentation that exists for Bioclipse</text>
         	</link>
       	</group>
  	</extensionContent>

	<page id="whatisBioclipse2" style="/intro/overview.css" style-id="page">
      <title style-id="intro-header">What is Bioclipse2</title>
      <include path="product:content/whatcanIdo.xhtml"/>
      <content />
	</page>
  	
	<page id="whatisBioclipse" style="/intro/overview.css" style-id="page">

      <title style-id="intro-header">What is Bioclipse</title>
      <include path="overview/navigation-links"/>
      <group id="page-content">
            <group id="content-header" label="What is Bioclipse" filteredFrom="swt">
            </group>
            <img src="images/jcpFull400.png" style-id="image-right" id="image-right"/>
            
            <text style-id="page-title" id="page-title" filteredFrom="html">What is Bioclipse</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            Bioclipse is a complete workbench for life science, including chemo- and bioinformatics 
            (e.g. small molecules, sequences, proteins, spectra) and provides 
            editing of chemical structures in 2D, interactive visualization of 
            chemical structures in 3D, conversion between common file formats in 
            life science, various analysis tools and much more - all 
            fully integrated into a user-friendly desktop application.
            </text>

            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            Bioclipse is a Java-based open source project based on the 
            Eclipse Rich Client Platform with its state-of-the-art plugin 
            architecture. This gives Bioclipse a huge advantage over other 
            systems, as it can easily be extended for adding 
            functionality in any direction.
            </text>

	        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">
            Bioclipse original publication
            </text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
			Ola Spjuth, Tobias Helmus, Egon L Willighagen, Stefan Kuhn, Martin Eklund, Johannes Wagener, Peter Murray-Rust, Christoph Steinbeck, Jarl E.S. Wikberg. 
            Bioclipse: An open source workbench for chemo- and bioinformatics. 
			BMC Bioinformatics 2007, 8:59 (22 February 2007)
            </text>
			
			<link label="Link to Bioclipse original article (Open Acces)" url="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1471-2105/8/59/abstract" id="weblink" style-id="weblink" />
            

      </group>
      </page>
      
	<page id="bioclipseConcepts" style="/intro/overview.css" style-id="page">
      <title style-id="intro-header">Bioclipse concepts</title>
      <include path="overview/navigation-links"/>
      <group id="page-content">
            <group id="content-header" label="Bioclipse concepts" filteredFrom="swt">
            </group>
            <text style-id="page-title" id="page-title" filteredFrom="html">Bioclipse concepts</text>
	    <!-- Add content here -->
        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Views</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            In Bioclipse, a View is a window that provides some graphical interface to present 
            something for a user, and might let him interact with it. Examples are the BioResource 
            Navigator, the Jmol View and the properties view.</text>
            <link label="More about Views (Bioclipse Help)" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showHelpTopic?id=/net.bioclipse.ui/html/workbench/wb_views.html" id="weblink" />
            

        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Editors</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            An Editor is focused on letting the user edit an underlying model and 
            follows the load-save cycle. An example is a simple editor for text-files, 
            but could also be more advanced such as a graphical objects editor like 
            the JchemPaint editor.</text>
            <link label="More about Editors (Bioclipse Help)" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showHelpTopic?id=/net.bioclipse.ui/html/workbench/wb_editors.html" id="weblink" />
            
        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Perspectives</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
			Perspectives are collections of editors and views that are grouped 
			into a page on screen, e.g. the Chemoinformatics perspective in Bioclipse 
			displays views and editors for working with molecules.
            </text>
            <link label="More about Perspectives (Bioclipse Help)" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showHelpTopic?id=/net.bioclipse.ui/html/workbench/wb_perspectiveBar.html" id="weblink" />
           
        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Plugins</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
			Bioclipse is completely made up of plugins. The core of Bioclipse is itself 
			a set of plugins with the most basic functionality, standard views, and 
			editors. The rest of the functionality is contributed via plugins. For example 
			does the Jmol plugin contribute a 3D-visualization based on Jmol, CDK provides 
			molecular management and analysis using the CDK libraries etc. This 
			means that a certain plugin must be installed in order for its 
			functionality to be available for the user. This is powerful in many 
			ways; A user may select to run only the desired plugins and not 
			clutter the workbench with unused functionality, and developers have a perfect 
			framework for plugging in their own extensions to Bioclipse and not interfere with other.
			</text>
			
			        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Workspace</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            The Bioclipse Navigator (aka Bioclipse Explorer) points to a special folder on 
            the computer called the "Workspace". In the workspace, Bioclipse has control over the 
            content and can listen and act on changes to files and folders in real time.
            
            The workspace contains a collection of resources. From the user's perspective, 
            there are three different types of resources: 
            projects, folders, and files. 
            
            A project is a collection of any number of files and folders. 
            It is a container for organizing other resources that relate to a specific area. 
            Files and folders are just like files and directories in the file system. 
            A folder contains other folders or files. 
            A file contains an arbitrary sequence of bytes. 
            There is only one Workspace open at any time.
            
            Projects contain files and folders, but not other projects. 
            Projects and folders are like directories in a file system.  
            When you delete a project, you will be asked whether you want to 
            delete all of the files and folders that it contains.  
            Deleting a folder from a project will delete the folder and all 
            of its children. 
            Deleting a file is analogous to deleting a file in the file system. 
            
			</text>
      </group>
      </page>

	<page id="licenses" style="/intro/overview.css" style-id="page">
      <title style-id="intro-header">Licensing</title>
      <include path="overview/navigation-links"/>
      <group id="page-content">
            <group id="content-header" label="Bioclipse licenses" filteredFrom="swt">
            </group>
            <text style-id="page-title" id="page-title" filteredFrom="html">Bioclipse licenses</text>
	    <!-- Add content here -->
        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">The Bioclipse Platform</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
			Bioclipse contains plugins, whose code uses a number of different licenses. The 
			Bioclipse platform, consisting of the core plugins, is licensed as EPL. The EPL 
			allows Bioclipse plugins to have other licenses, including commercial.
            </text>
       		<link label="Link to EPL license" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/openURL?url=html/epl-v10.html&amp;?pluginId=net.bioclipse.ui" class="link" id="weblink" style-id="content-link" />

        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">EPL-GPL Statement</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
			The GNU Public License (GPL) is a bit special here, and is considered 
			not to be compatible with the EPL. Indeed, a EPL licensed plugin may not 
			use GPL code, which is why the bc_biojava plugin is licensed GPL. Making a 
			GPL project based on EPL code is considered not possible too, while the 
			EPL puts some restrictions on the licensing patents, which are incompatible 
			with the GPL. However, the Bioclipse project considers plugins not to extend 
			the Bioclipse platform, consisting of the bioclipse + com.tools.logging plugins, 
			and are not considered a derivative product, and we hereby approve GPL 
			licensed plugins for Bioclipse.             
            </text>

      </group>
      </page>
      
      	<page id="documentation" style="/intro/overview.css" style-id="page">
      <title style-id="intro-header">Documentation</title>
      <include path="overview/navigation-links"/>
      <group id="page-content">
            <group id="content-header" label="Sources for documentation" filteredFrom="swt">
            </group>
            <text style-id="page-title" id="page-title" filteredFrom="html">Sources of documentation</text>

        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Bioclipse help system</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            The Bioclipse help system is the main resource for documentation of Bioclipse. 
            Here you find a searchable collection of documents, tutorials, and 
            reference documentation for the various installed features. 
            After you download and install a new feature, it might be good to 
            re-visit the Help system as new documentation might be available.
            The Bioclipse help system is accesible from inside the Bioclipse Workbench 
            via the menu Help > Help Contents.
            </text>
            <link label="Link to Bioclipse Help" url="http://org.eclipse.ui.intro/showHelp" id="about" />
            

        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Bioclipse Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)</text>
       		<link label="Link to FAQ on Bioclipse wiki" url="http://wiki.bioclipse.net/index.php?title=FAQ" id="weblink" style-id="content-link" />

        <text style-id="page-content" id="page-content">Bioclipse Welcome page</text>
            <text style-id="page-description" id="page-description">
            This is the page you are currently reading! In the top menu you have many 
            alternatives to discover the many features of Bioclipse.
            </text>

      </group>
      </page>

</introContent>